<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics Researcher | Machine Learning Engineer</title>
    <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics Researcher | Machine Learning Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 23:12:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://atg-abhishek.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of my work</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/workdetails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 23:12:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/workdetails/</guid>
      <description>Current affiliations  Founder, Montreal AI Ethics Institute and a principal investigator for several projects happening at the Montreal AI Ethics Institute.
 Machine Learning Engineer, Microsoft on the Commercial Software Engineering (CSE) team at Microsoft where I work on machine learning projects involving both Azure ML services and open-source implementations. The hallmarks of the CSE team are that we operate in a “code-with” model with our customers. The team is deeply technical and highly specialized in solving the toughest technical challenges faced by Microsoft’s customers and the team follows an open-sourcing model to contribute the code and insights to the community from our engagements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Work</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/currentwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/currentwork/</guid>
      <description>Featured picture courtesy of the McGill Physics Hackathon
Primary areas of research focus:  Participatory design approaches to machine learning - designing asynchronous collaborative approaches leveraging participatory design methodology mediated through bot interfaces to build more inclusive AI systems.
 Privacy – bridging the gap between the legal and technical domains to advise on privacy legislation amendments and assessing privacy implications of new technological solutions like contact- and proximity-tracing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of the Brookfield IIE
As seen in All copyrights and trademarks belong to the owners of the images
Privacy and Security in AI REWORK White Paper Series
Paper Link
AI Ethics: Inclusivity in Smart Cities Montreal AI Ethics Institute Presented at WEF 4IR 2018 Summit
Article Link
Artificial Intelligence as a Force For Good Stanford Social Innovation Review Technology Section
Article Link
Inclusive Design - Methods to ensure a high degree of participation in Artificial Intelligence (AI) systems Oxford Internet Institute Oxford University - Connected Life 2018</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:24:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/conferences/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of REWORK
SPEAKER NORTH AMERICAN REGIONAL SUMMIT (AMERICAN UNIVERSITY OF BEIRUT) MONTREAL 2018 The Future of AI: Utopia or Dystopia?
NARS AUB Summit Montreal 2018
PANELIST TECHSTARS MONTREAL 2018 Panel on regulations and legal frameworks on data privacy
Invite only event
PANELIST REWORK AI FOR GOVERNMENT SUMMIT TORONTO 2018 Should Government regulate AI?
REWORK AI for Government Summit Toronto 2018
PANELIST REWORK AI FOR GOVERNMENT SUMMIT TORONTO 2018 AI for Law Enforcement and Fraud</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Coverage</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/mediacoverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:22:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/mediacoverage/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of AI for Good Global Summit
As seen in All copyrights and trademarks belong to the owners of the images
Researchers propose framework to measure AI’s social and environmental impact VentureBeat June 12, 2020
Article Link
A.I. engineers should spend time training not just algorithms, but also the humans who use them Fortune May 5, 2020
Article Link
Ethics and artificial intelligence: These researchers say tech has to have a moral backbone CBC June 20, 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:21:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/videos/</guid>
      <description>Screenshot from the BorealisAI Northern Frontier Series featured interview on AI ethics
Interview with BorealisAI BorealisAI Interview with BorealisAI that took a dive into the threat automation poses to job loss based on the current science, whether bias is the biggest problem we face in responsible AI, and what we should consider reasonable trade-offs for improving fairness.

Framework for the ethical development of AI Montreal AI Symposium Presentation at the Montreal AI Symposium on a framework for ethical development of AI systems</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>