<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics Researcher | Machine Learning Engineer</title>
    <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics Researcher | Machine Learning Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 23:12:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://atg-abhishek.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of my work</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/workdetails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 23:12:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/workdetails/</guid>
      <description>Current affiliations  Founder, Montreal AI Ethics Institute and a principal investigator for several projects happening at the Montreal AI Ethics Institute.
 Machine Learning Engineer, Microsoft on the Commercial Software Engineering (CSE) team at Microsoft where I work on machine learning projects involving both Azure ML services and open-source implementations. The hallmarks of the CSE team are that we operate in a “code-with” model with our customers. The team is deeply technical and highly specialized in solving the toughest technical challenges faced by Microsoft’s customers and the team follows an open-sourcing model to contribute the code and insights to the community from our engagements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Work</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/currentwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/currentwork/</guid>
      <description>Featured picture courtesy of the McGill Physics Hackathon
Primary areas of research focus:  ML Retrospectives - a novel approach to making machine learning research transparent and accessible to colleagues in the scientific community. An emphasis on being retrospective about prior work and being comfortable with mistakes, transforming them into stepping stones for further scientific endeavours. For more information, please take a look here. This idea has been hosted as workshops at NeurIPS 2019, ICML 2020, and will be hosted at NeurIPS 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of the Brookfield IIE
As seen in All copyrights and trademarks belong to the owners of the images
Why free and open source software (FOSS) should be the future of Responsible AI Towards Data Science In a highly fragemented software ecosystem, this article explores the role that FOSS can play in holding the field more accountable in the tools that are built for Responsible AI
Article Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:24:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/conferences/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of REWORK
SPEAKER MCGILL DESAUTELS WOMEN&amp;rsquo;S GRADUATE ASSOCIATION AND DESAUTELS BUSINESS TECHNOLOGY CLUB WORKSHOP Presentation on the subject of bias and AI ethics along with required organizational changes from a business and management perspective to realize these changes in practice
Workshop for Desautels students
SPEAKER RAJARATNAM SCHOOL OF INTERNATIONAL STUDIES - NANYANG TECHNOLOGICAL UNIVERSITY AI CONFERENCE Presentation on the subject of mutualism as a way to build trustworthy AI at a global level</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Coverage</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/mediacoverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:22:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/mediacoverage/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of AI for Good Global Summit
As seen in                                                        All copyrights and trademarks belong to the owners of the images</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:21:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/videos/</guid>
      <description>Screenshot from the BorealisAI Northern Frontier Series featured interview on AI ethics
Civic competence against the invisible hand of AI TEDx Talk In this TEDx talk, I walk through the notion of civic competence as a way of creating broad-based awareness on the harms that can arise from AI systems and equipping everyday people with the appropriate knowledge to challenge the systems to create a more just, fair, and well-functioning society.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>