<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics | Machine Learning on Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics Researcher | Machine Learning Engineer</title>
    <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics | Machine Learning on Abhishek Gupta | AI Ethics Researcher | Machine Learning Engineer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 23:12:09 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview of my work</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/workdetails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 23:12:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/workdetails/</guid>
      <description>Current affiliations  Founder, Montreal AI Ethics Institute and a principal investigator for several projects happening at the Montreal AI Ethics Institute.
 Machine Learning Engineer, Microsoft on the Commercial Software Engineering (CSE) team at Microsoft where I work on machine learning projects involving both Azure ML services and open-source implementations. The hallmarks of the CSE team are that we operate in a “code-with” model with our customers. The team is deeply technical and highly specialized in solving the toughest technical challenges faced by Microsoft’s customers and the team follows an open-sourcing model to contribute the code and insights to the community from our engagements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Current Work</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/currentwork/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/currentwork/</guid>
      <description>Featured picture courtesy of the McGill Physics Hackathon
Primary areas of research focus:  ML Retrospectives - a novel approach to making machine learning research transparent and accessible to colleagues in the scientific community. An emphasis on being retrospective about prior work and being comfortable with mistakes, transforming them into stepping stones for further scientific endeavours. For more information, please take a look here. This idea has been hosted as workshops at NeurIPS 2019, ICML 2020, and will be hosted at NeurIPS 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/publications/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of the Brookfield IIE
As seen in All copyrights and trademarks belong to the owners of the images
How data governance technologies can democratize data sharing for community well-being Data &amp;amp; Policy Journal, Cambridge University Press Data sharing efforts to allow underserved groups and organizations to overcome the concentration of power in our data landscape. A few special organizations, due to their data monopolies and resources, are able to decide which problems to solve and how to solve them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talks</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/conferences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:24:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/conferences/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of REWORK
SPEAKER Nonviolence International Southeast Asia Conference 2021 Ethics in the use of AI in war
Invite-only conference
MODERATOR The State of AI Ethics Panel May 2021 Panel discussing the research and reporting in Q2 2021 based on The State of AI Ethics Report Volume 4 published by the Montreal AI Ethics Institute
Video link
SPEAKER csv,conf,v6 Talk on The Lab Notebook: Bringing Science Back to Data Science Conference Link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media Coverage</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/mediacoverage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:22:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/mediacoverage/</guid>
      <description>Featured image courtesy of AI for Good Global Summit
As seen in                                                        All copyrights and trademarks belong to the owners of the images</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:21:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://atg-abhishek.github.io/about/videos/</guid>
      <description>Screenshot from the BorealisAI Northern Frontier Series featured interview on AI ethics
Future of Work and Disability: Bias in Candidate Selection Inclusive Design Research Center, OCAD University Workshop: Addressing Bias in Machine Learning Models on Candidate Selection
In this module, participants explored policy through a co-design activity, working in groups to co-create approaches to AI and ML challenges in employment systems. Abhishek Gupta helped guide us through this activity. Abhishek introduced and framed the co-design activity that engaged teams and encouraged them to work through practical situations and challenges related to policies and standards around employment, disability and AI.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>